<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>agency Archives | Alex Taylor</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/agency/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>by Alex Taylor</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 08:44:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>
	<item>
		<title>“The promiscuity of interaction”</title>
		<link>/promiscuity-of-interaction/</link>
					<comments>/promiscuity-of-interaction/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Taylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 08:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HCI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interaction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intra-action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[STS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a brief comment on&#160;a meeting Barry Brown and I hosted at Microsoft Research Cambridge, titled . “Interaction as a&#160;a promiscuous concept”: it’s Stuart Reeves’ phrasing that nicely captures the sentiment of our small meeting’s discussions. The collection of short talks and the emphasis given to talking (and not just lecturing), gave rise to [...]</p>
<p><a class="btn btn-secondary understrap-read-more-link" href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/">Read More...<span class="screen-reader-text"> from “The promiscuity of interaction”</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/">“The promiscuity of interaction”</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Alex Taylor</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>This is a brief comment on&nbsp;a meeting <a href="http://barbro.tumblr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Barry Brown</a> and I hosted at Microsoft Research Cambridge, titled <a id="tippy_tip0_6153_anchor"></a>. <a id="tippy_tip1_9561_anchor"></a></p></blockquote>
<p>“Interaction as a&nbsp;a promiscuous concept”: it’s <a href="http://www.cs.nott.ac.uk/~pszsr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stuart Reeves’</a> <a id="tippy_tip2_7071_anchor"></a> phrasing that nicely captures the sentiment of our small meeting’s discussions. The collection of short talks and the emphasis given to talking (and not just lecturing), gave rise to a language of critical but positive reflection. Rather than deliberating on an ‘after’ or ‘post’ interaction turn or wave in HCI, interaction was seen to still offer a great deal. The consensus (led by positions from <a href="https://openlab.ncl.ac.uk/people/ndk37" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">David Kirk</a>, <a href="http://www.abigaildurrant.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Abi Durrant</a>&nbsp;<a id="tippy_tip3_2813_anchor"></a>, <a href="http://www.gold.ac.uk/design/staff/gaver/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bill Gaver</a> and <a href="http://www.cs.nott.ac.uk/~pszsr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stuart</a>) was it provides us with a device or machinery in common, and, conceptually, there remains much to do with the word that keeps us open to new domains and indeed new (design) possibilities. Here, I’m reminded of Isabelle Stengers use of the phrase a “tool for thinking”.<a id="tippy_tip4_9995_anchor"></a> It certainly appears interaction (still) provides us with just such a tool.<br>
And yet I felt there was a shared frustration<span id="more-1042"></span> — or at least a frustration in myself — of what limits come with using the word interaction. With it, I find it hard not to feel bound to <em>mediation</em> as a central matter of concern, and alongside that being drawn to a fixed ‘divide’ between humans and machines that must be bridged or somehow solved. For me, this brings to mind Karen Barad’s <a id="tippy_tip5_274_anchor"></a>’ in which she introduces “<em>intra-action</em>” to purposefully contrast it with the “the usual ‘interaction’, which assumes that there are separate individual agencies that precede their interaction”. <a id="tippy_tip6_977_anchor"></a></p>
<div style="width: 40%; margin-left: 8px; float: right;">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Shared 1 of my fave texts by Star at <a href="https://twitter.com/alxndrt">@alxndrt</a> ‘HCI after interaction’ conf at <a href="https://twitter.com/Microsoft">@Microsoft</a> yest. Also good stickergame <a href="https://t.co/6aa3HUWKN7">pic.twitter.com/6aa3HUWKN7</a></p>
<p>— kat jungnickel (@katjungnickel) <a href="https://twitter.com/katjungnickel/status/707949925099827201">March 10, 2016</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async charset="utf-8"></script>
</p></div>
<p>With interaction, it seems we also struggle to account for the worlds that are instantly and irrevocably entangled in our ‘interactions’ with machines, the scales of order (<a href="http://www.ericlaurier.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eric Laurier</a>) or scaling (<a href="http://www.alexwilkie.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Alex Wilkie</a>) that always looms large. Among her reflections on the day, <a href="http://www.katjungnickel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kat Jungnickel</a> reminded us of Leigh Star’s wonderful “<em>Cultures of Computing</em>” in which she writes evocatively:</p>
<blockquote><p>“<a id="tippy_tip7_9165_anchor"></a>, typing this, my neck aches and I am curled in an uncomfortable position. I try to think about my fingertips and the chips inside this Macintosh as a seamless “web of computing,’ to use Kling and Scacchi’s classic phrase (1982). But chips make me think of the eyesight of women in Singapore and Korea, going blind during the process of crafting the fiddly little wires; of ‘clean rooms’ I have visited in Silicon Valley and the Netherlands, where people dressed like astronauts etch bits of silicon and fabricate complex Sandwiches of information and logic. I think of the silence of my European ancestors who wore Chinese embroidery, marveling at its intricate complexity, the near impossible stitches woven over a lifetime with the eyesight of another generation of Asian women. I think, I want my body to include these experiences. If we are to have ubiquitous, wireless computing in the future, perhaps it is time to have a less boring idea of the body right now—a body politic, not just the substrate for meetings or toys.” <a id="tippy_tip8_2566_anchor"></a></p></blockquote>
<p>So, yes, interaction analysis, such as that from <a href="http://ses-perso.telecom-paristech.fr/licoppe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Christian Licoppe</a>, offers us some compelling tools for examining the unfolding detail of mundane activities, but how do we extend these analyses to account for a wider ethics (<a href="http://www.ucl.ac.uk/uclic/people/y_rogers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Yvonne Rogers</a>), the “body right now”, and indeed our own productive roles in enacting these cuts (<a href="http://www.katjungnickel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kat</a>)? How might we focus our attentions not on the agencies intrinsic in humans and things (before interaction, if there could be such a thing), but where and how agency is brought into being (<a href="http://www.alexwilkie.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Alex Wilkie</a> <a id="tippy_tip9_6266_anchor"></a> and <a href="http://sydney.edu.au/arts/staff/profiles/mike.michael.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mike Michael</a>).<br>
I ask, then, is this the point of inflection? As we turn our minds and bodies to very present technocultures that surround us, ones where things take on new agencies (<a href="http://www.xrce.xerox.com/About-XRCE/People/David-Martin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">David Martin</a>), have the capacity to push back (<a href="http://www.io.tudelft.nl/en/organisation/personal-profiles/professors/giaccardi-e/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Elisa Giaccardi</a> <a id="tippy_tip10_6906_anchor"></a>), and where data infrastructures and algorithms are pervasive (<a href="http://airilampinen.fi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Airi Lampinen</a><a id="tippy_tip11_4826_anchor"></a> and <a href="http://barbro.tumblr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Barry</a>), these weaknesses become increasingly prescient. How are we to think with the “usual” interaction here? How does a preoccupation with a human-centred interaction with machines give us the capacity to see things and practices that stitch and weave across geographies and over lifetimes? Do our promiscuous interactions, if you will, leave us room for thinking and making around these sprawling, always provisional cosmopolitical<a id="tippy_tip12_776_anchor"></a> land- and time-scapes?<br>
Here, might we sketch out a way to move on in which the uses and design of technology become ways to extend our thinking about and with promiscuous interactions? These interactions—from small scale, one-to-one tinkerings, makings, and repairs, to movements and transformations at scale—aren’t so much things that follow knowing (or for that matter produce what we know); the divide here isn’t between knowing and interacting. Rather they are active processes through which we come to be in the world, not just in what we know, but how we organise ourselves, what we value and care for, etc. We might grapple with things, materially, at the one-to-one scale, but we are forever working with their extending web of entanglements (Abi Durrant). This, we might say, is to take interaction seriously, to understand it beyond the object of study and see it more as a productive reconfiguration of what for many of us have become the troubling disciplinary divisions between the social sciences, design and computing. What we have is an inventive orientation to interaction; whether it’s the detailed study of car drivers using Facebook (Christian Licoppe) or the economic and political assemblages&nbsp;emerging through widely distributed Uber and AirBnB use (Barry and Airi Lampinen), interaction gives us a way to cast things differently and get closer, so to speak, to the entanglements.</p>
<div class="tippy" data-title="HCI after interaction" data-showheader="false" data-anchor="#tippy_tip0_6153_anchor">See <a href="/back-to-interaction/">this post</a> as one source for the discussion.</div>
<div class="tippy" data-title="1" data-href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/#foot_text_1042_1" data-class="annie_footnoteRef annie_custom" data-name="foot_loc_1042_1" data-showheader data-anchor="#tippy_tip1_9561_anchor">Kindly attended by, Andy Boucher, Barry Brown, Rob Comber, Anna Cox, Abi Durrant, Bill Gaver, Elisa Giaccardi, Kat Jungnickel, Dave Kirk, Airi Lampinen, Eric Laurier, Lucian Leahu, Christian Licoppe, Dave Martin, Mike Michael, Marianna Obrist, Stuart Reeves, Yvonne Rogers, Francesca Salvadori, Anja Thieme, Tony Weiser and Alex Wilkie.</div>
<div class="tippy" data-title="2" data-href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/#foot_text_1042_2" data-class="annie_footnoteRef annie_custom" data-name="foot_loc_1042_2" data-showheader data-anchor="#tippy_tip2_7071_anchor">Stuart has posted the notes to his talk <a href="http://notesonresearch.tumblr.com/post/142011592823/talking-about-interaction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>. He&nbsp;has suggested this as a complimentary reading: Anderson, B. and Sharrock, W. (2013). <a href="http://www.sharrockandanderson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/PostModernism-Social-Science-Technology-2012.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PostModernism, Social Science &amp; Technology</a>.</div>
<div class="tippy" data-title="3" data-href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/#foot_text_1042_3" data-class="annie_footnoteRef annie_custom" data-name="foot_loc_1042_3" data-showheader data-anchor="#tippy_tip3_2813_anchor">Abi referenced the piece “<a href="http://www.hookerandkitchen.com/edgetown/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Edge Town</a>” by Hooker and Kitchen (2004), in her short talk. She has also suggested E. M. Foster’s ‘<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Machine_Stops" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Machine Stops</a>’ for further reading. As she explains: [t]his is because this novella conveys the ideas we discussed about making-and-describing the macro and micro features of a world (of complex mediated interactions) and, dare I say, the ‘local and global’. &nbsp;(With the 1:1 scale features of &nbsp;interaction being the stuff that designers can really work with.&nbsp;<i>It manages to convey the complexity of a socio-technical system through depicting a few moments of relatively simple interaction with ‘the machine’</i>. &nbsp;The story also presents truly entangled human and non human bodies and their politics, ethics, dependencies, faith — and deals more specifically with implications around&nbsp;<i>transparency</i>&nbsp;within those mediated interactions. This is despite being of it’s time and assuming certain differences between people and the natural world, and ‘man and machine’.</div>
<div class="tippy" data-title="4" data-href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/#foot_text_1042_4" data-class="annie_footnoteRef annie_custom" data-name="foot_loc_1042_4" data-showheader data-anchor="#tippy_tip4_9995_anchor">See, Stengers, I. (2013). Introductory notes on an ecology of practices. <em>Cultural Studies Review</em>, 11(1), 183–196.</div>
<div class="tippy" data-title="profound conceptual shift" data-showheader="false" data-anchor="#tippy_tip5_274_anchor">From “[T]he usual ‘interaction,’ which presumes the prior existence of independent entities”. Barad, K. (2003). <a href="http://doi.org/10.1086/345321" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Posthumanist Performativity: Toward an Understanding of How Matter Comes to Matter.</a> <i>Signs: Journal of Women in Culture and Society</i>, <i>28</i>(3), p.815.</div>
<div class="tippy" data-title="5" data-href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/#foot_text_1042_5" data-class="annie_footnoteRef annie_custom" data-name="foot_loc_1042_5" data-showheader data-anchor="#tippy_tip6_977_anchor">See, Barad, K. M. (2011). <a href="http://doi.org/10.1177/0306312711406317" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Erasers and erasures: Pinch’s unfortunate ‘uncertainty principle’</a>. <i>Social Studies of Science</i>, <i>41</i>(3), p. 451.</div>
<div class="tippy" data-title="Right now" data-showheader="false" data-anchor="#tippy_tip7_9165_anchor">See <a href="https://twitter.com/katjungnickel" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kat’s</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/katjungnickel/status/712220900637208576" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tweeted</a> photos of the original text.</div>
<div class="tippy" data-title="6" data-href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/#foot_text_1042_6" data-class="annie_footnoteRef annie_custom" data-name="foot_loc_1042_6" data-showheader data-anchor="#tippy_tip8_2566_anchor">See, Star, S. L. (1995). <em>The Cultures of Computing</em>. Blackwell Publishers, Inc., pp. 2–3.</div>
<div class="tippy" data-title="7" data-href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/#foot_text_1042_7" data-class="annie_footnoteRef annie_custom" data-name="foot_loc_1042_7" data-showheader data-anchor="#tippy_tip9_6266_anchor">Alex suggests this for further reading: Latour, B. (2007). <a href="http://sss.sagepub.com/content/37/5/811.full.pdf+html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Turning around politics</a>: A note on Gerard de Vries’ paper. <em>Social Studies of Science</em>, 37(5), 811–820.</div>
<div class="tippy" data-title="8" data-href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/#foot_text_1042_8" data-class="annie_footnoteRef annie_custom" data-name="foot_loc_1042_8" data-showheader data-anchor="#tippy_tip10_6906_anchor">Elisa has given us access to her forthcoming book chapter: <a href="/m/1078" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Things as Co-ethnographers: Implications of a Thing Perspective for Design and Anthropology</a>, to To appear in R.C. Smith et al. (eds) (2016) <em>Design Anthropology Futures</em>, London: Bloomsbury.</div>
<div class="tippy" data-title="9" data-href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/#foot_text_1042_9" data-class="annie_footnoteRef annie_custom" data-name="foot_loc_1042_9" data-showheader data-anchor="#tippy_tip11_4826_anchor">Airi has suggested reading: Gillespie, T. (2014). “<a href="http://culturedigitally.org/2012/11/the-relevance-of-algorithms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Relevance of Algorithms</a>.” In <em>Media Technologies: Essays on Communication, Materiality, and Society</em>, edited by Tarleton Gillespie, Pablo Boczkowski, and Kirsten Foot, 167–194. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press. Seaver, N. (2013). “<a href="http://nickseaver.net/s/seaverMiT8.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Knowing Algorithms</a>.” In <em>Media in Transition 8</em>. Cambridge, MA. She has also recommended a link to the excellent <a href="http://socialmediacollective.org/reading-lists/critical-algorithm-studies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reading list</a> on algorithms that Tarleton Gillespie and Nick Seaver have compiled on MSR’s <a href="http://socialmediacollective.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Social Media Collective’s website</a>.</div>
<div class="tippy" data-title="10" data-href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/#foot_text_1042_10" data-class="annie_footnoteRef annie_custom" data-name="foot_loc_1042_10" data-showheader data-anchor="#tippy_tip12_776_anchor">Thanks to Alex Wilkie, who won (some of) us around to Stengers’ and Bruno Latours’ <em>Cosmopolitics</em>. See, Latour, B. (2004). Whose Cosmos, Which Cosmopolitics? Comments on the Peace Terms of Ulrich Beck. <em>Common Knowledge</em>, 10(3), 450–462. And Stengers, I. (2010). <em>Cosmopolitics I</em>, Bononno, R (trans.), Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/">“The promiscuity of interaction”</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Alex Taylor</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/promiscuity-of-interaction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
