<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: On Simone’s ‘people as infrastructure’	</title>
	<atom:link href="http://ast.io/reading-simones-people-infrastructure/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://ast.io/reading-simones-people-infrastructure/</link>
	<description>by Alex Taylor</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 11:48:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: People as (Infra)structure &#124; Making-of Social Innovation		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/reading-simones-people-infrastructure/#comment-14</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[People as (Infra)structure &#124; Making-of Social Innovation]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 11:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=336#comment-14</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] the post by Alex Tailor on an article by AbdouMaliq Simone, titled &#8211; People as Infrastructure: Intersecting Fragments [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[…] the post by Alex Tailor on an article by AbdouMaliq Simone, titled – People as Infrastructure: Intersecting Fragments […]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: alwaysalready		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/reading-simones-people-infrastructure/#comment-13</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alwaysalready]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 22:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=336#comment-13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tensions, Tenison - it&#039;s so apt! Thanks Daniela. Nice points. I&#039;d love to see how we could keep these kinds of frictions going in the project and at the same time see them as productive.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tensions, Tenison — it’s so apt! Thanks Daniela. Nice points. I’d love to see how we could keep these kinds of frictions going in the project and at the same time see them as productive.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Anonymous		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/reading-simones-people-infrastructure/#comment-12</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anonymous]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 06:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=336#comment-12</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Okay, so &#039;enter&#039; equals submit. Learning slowly. :)
To continue… I also agree with Alex that Simone&#039;s heavy use of the term &#039;collaboration&#039; to describe residents&#039; interactions sometimes skirts issues of lawlessness connected to the upheaval and distress in the city, casting violence as sometimes banal and even necessary. But still compelling is how these &#039;social collaborations&#039; could serve as &quot;occasions to be public,&quot; as in the city&#039;s night markets where one can &quot;situate oneself so one can assess what is happening… without constituting a threat&quot; (p.427). In these spaces, residents interpret, fix, and navigate in ways that produce unique forms of social visibility.
But what I found most useful in this piece is Simone&#039;s treatment of &quot;community building,&quot; which he develops as a kind of red herring. Projects initiated by municipals like the Metropolitan Council of Johannesburg can micromanage, becoming &quot;a peripheral disciplinary exercise that distracts residents from developing the real skills that they need to survive&quot;  (p.420). This made me wonder how the tension road project (or others in HCI that strive to bring questions of community engagement to tech development) might account for this straining of political and economic relations - or whether they contribute to these &#039;tensions&#039; (hehe) instead.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Okay, so ‘enter’ equals submit. Learning slowly. 🙂<br>
To continue… I also agree with Alex that Simone’s heavy use of the term ‘collaboration’ to describe residents’ interactions sometimes skirts issues of lawlessness connected to the upheaval and distress in the city, casting violence as sometimes banal and even necessary. But still compelling is how these ‘social collaborations’ could serve as “occasions to be public,” as in the city’s night markets where one can “situate oneself so one can assess what is happening… without constituting a threat” (p.427). In these spaces, residents interpret, fix, and navigate in ways that produce unique forms of social visibility.<br>
But what I found most useful in this piece is Simone’s treatment of “community building,” which he develops as a kind of red herring. Projects initiated by municipals like the Metropolitan Council of Johannesburg can micromanage, becoming “a peripheral disciplinary exercise that distracts residents from developing the real skills that they need to survive”  (p.420). This made me wonder how the tension road project (or others in HCI that strive to bring questions of community engagement to tech development) might account for this straining of political and economic relations — or whether they contribute to these ‘tensions’ (hehe) instead.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Anonymous		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/reading-simones-people-infrastructure/#comment-11</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anonymous]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 05:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=336#comment-11</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[(Sorry, I somehow pressed submit prematurely!)]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>(Sorry, I somehow pressed submit prematurely!)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Anonymous		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/reading-simones-people-infrastructure/#comment-9</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anonymous]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 05:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=336#comment-9</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sorry to be picking this up relatively late. I really enjoyed the ethnographic accounts in this piece, particularly the meandering along Qaurtz street, which led me to see Simon&#039;s presentation as a kind of disciplining in itself of the arguments he attempts to make. I totally agree with Alex&#039;s critique around the multiple articles that could be written about one or more of Simone&#039;s arguments.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry to be picking this up relatively late. I really enjoyed the ethnographic accounts in this piece, particularly the meandering along Qaurtz street, which led me to see Simon’s presentation as a kind of disciplining in itself of the arguments he attempts to make. I totally agree with Alex’s critique around the multiple articles that could be written about one or more of Simone’s arguments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Anonymous		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/reading-simones-people-infrastructure/#comment-10</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anonymous]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 05:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=336#comment-10</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sorry to be picking this up relatively late. I really enjoyed the ethnographic accounts in this piece, particularly the meandering along Qaurtz street, which led me to see Simon&#039;s presentation as a kind of disciplining in itself of the arguments he attempts to make. I totally agree with Alex&#039;s critique around the multiple articles that could be written about one or more of Simone&#039;s arguments.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry to be picking this up relatively late. I really enjoyed the ethnographic accounts in this piece, particularly the meandering along Qaurtz street, which led me to see Simon’s presentation as a kind of disciplining in itself of the arguments he attempts to make. I totally agree with Alex’s critique around the multiple articles that could be written about one or more of Simone’s arguments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: alwaysalready		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/reading-simones-people-infrastructure/#comment-8</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alwaysalready]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 14:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=336#comment-8</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hard to know who&#039;s posted what here, but a few responses/reflections.
I like the idea that organisations and territories are performed categories, and that these may in some way describe or enact operations. This muddies the distinctions between things, processes and practices. I&#039;d like to find some compelling examples where the data doesn&#039;t try to tidy up the subject categories and leaves them messy and, at times, in tension. It&#039;s a challenge to think about how this might be represented intelligibly, but it does seem a challenge worth pursuing. The alternative are data representations that persist in telling us what we already know - and we all know there are plenty of those around.
The transience of the street is something we&#039;ve discussed but never quite got a handle on. My hope is it might develop in some of the historical archive work and how this sits against contemporary and everyday narratives produced either by the residents or data we collect. Siân&#039;s been giving some thought to the temporal aspects of the project and I think this is going to be something to work up.
The issues raised about how the municipal entities and the very different (codified) understandings they have of Jo&#039;berg&#039;s streets to what appears to be happening on the ground definitely has some relevance to the Tenison Road project. Of course the scale and degree of vice/crime is of an entirely different order, but nevertheless, I think not surprisingly there are multiple views of the street being enacted by the residents, developers, local council, etc. Again, we have definitely touched on these things and they will, I&#039;m sure, come up again. Our concern should I guess be for how to surface them in the data work and allow them to be put to productive use. ]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hard to know who’s posted what here, but a few responses/reflections.<br>
I like the idea that organisations and territories are performed categories, and that these may in some way describe or enact operations. This muddies the distinctions between things, processes and practices. I’d like to find some compelling examples where the data doesn’t try to tidy up the subject categories and leaves them messy and, at times, in tension. It’s a challenge to think about how this might be represented intelligibly, but it does seem a challenge worth pursuing. The alternative are data representations that persist in telling us what we already know — and we all know there are plenty of those around.<br>
The transience of the street is something we’ve discussed but never quite got a handle on. My hope is it might develop in some of the historical archive work and how this sits against contemporary and everyday narratives produced either by the residents or data we collect. Siân’s been giving some thought to the temporal aspects of the project and I think this is going to be something to work up.<br>
The issues raised about how the municipal entities and the very different (codified) understandings they have of Jo’berg’s streets to what appears to be happening on the ground definitely has some relevance to the Tenison Road project. Of course the scale and degree of vice/crime is of an entirely different order, but nevertheless, I think not surprisingly there are multiple views of the street being enacted by the residents, developers, local council, etc. Again, we have definitely touched on these things and they will, I’m sure, come up again. Our concern should I guess be for how to surface them in the data work and allow them to be put to productive use. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Anonymous		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/reading-simones-people-infrastructure/#comment-7</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anonymous]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 14:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=336#comment-7</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PS The above is meant to be bullet points! Sorry about the formatting.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>PS The above is meant to be bullet points! Sorry about the formatting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Anonymous		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/reading-simones-people-infrastructure/#comment-6</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anonymous]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 14:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=336#comment-6</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thanks for initiating this discussion Alex. It was a really thought-provoking read and a offers a very different take on what city and street life can be. A few things stood out for me, in relation to the our own project.
- The idea that organisations and territories appear bounded, but that this boundedness is a &#039;performance&#039; rather than &#039;a description of actual operations&#039; (p. 422). This boundedness is made visible  in Simone&#039;s account of Jo&#039;berg in particular ways - nationality being a prominent factor - but I think this statement has much broader relevance. It&#039;s always going to be the case that territories overlap and that boundaries between them will be fluid, being mitigated by particular interpersonal relationships. There is a sense that, in our project, different organisations and territories are broadly recognised (indeed, some are explicitly defined), and that the two overlap. I wonder to what extent these categories are performed and how, and to what extent they can be seen as a description of operations, and what these operations are. I wonder too, if and how this could be represented as data.
- Relating to this, I was struck by the idea that individuals in Jo&#039;berg are &#039;in some way a competitor .. based on self-interest, self-protection, and camaraderie, not on a long-term investment in the cultivation of a place of operation&#039; (p. 423). I find it interesting that camaraderie is in the middle of this sentence, as though this is a way of keeping things running smoothly without actually making any real investment. Camaraderie here seems superficial, and perhaps this is magnified by the fact that even where good relationships form, the people that they are formed with aren&#039;t likely to stay in the area. Themes of community and transience are both applicable in our project, as is the notion of self-interest. It&#039;s interesting to consider how these intersect - what do transient populations as opposed to those firmly rooted in the street hope to get from the project? How is this manifested in relation to data?
	- As a final point, the tension between making things visible as a way of supporting administration and the use of resources is interesting. I think we&#039;ve seen this in some of our meetings; it&#039;s been expressed that better knowledge of the resources available in the street would support flexible and shared use of them. We haven&#039;t really considered what the complexities of doing so are, and I think this could feed nicely into some of our broader discussions about accountability and openness.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks for initiating this discussion Alex. It was a really thought-provoking read and a offers a very different take on what city and street life can be. A few things stood out for me, in relation to the our own project.<br>
— The idea that organisations and territories appear bounded, but that this boundedness is a ‘performance’ rather than ‘a description of actual operations’ (p. 422). This boundedness is made visible  in Simone’s account of Jo’berg in particular ways — nationality being a prominent factor — but I think this statement has much broader relevance. It’s always going to be the case that territories overlap and that boundaries between them will be fluid, being mitigated by particular interpersonal relationships. There is a sense that, in our project, different organisations and territories are broadly recognised (indeed, some are explicitly defined), and that the two overlap. I wonder to what extent these categories are performed and how, and to what extent they can be seen as a description of operations, and what these operations are. I wonder too, if and how this could be represented as data.<br>
— Relating to this, I was struck by the idea that individuals in Jo’berg are ‘in some way a competitor .. based on self-interest, self-protection, and camaraderie, not on a long-term investment in the cultivation of a place of operation’ (p. 423). I find it interesting that camaraderie is in the middle of this sentence, as though this is a way of keeping things running smoothly without actually making any real investment. Camaraderie here seems superficial, and perhaps this is magnified by the fact that even where good relationships form, the people that they are formed with aren’t likely to stay in the area. Themes of community and transience are both applicable in our project, as is the notion of self-interest. It’s interesting to consider how these intersect — what do transient populations as opposed to those firmly rooted in the street hope to get from the project? How is this manifested in relation to data?<br>
	— As a final point, the tension between making things visible as a way of supporting administration and the use of resources is interesting. I think we’ve seen this in some of our meetings; it’s been expressed that better knowledge of the resources available in the street would support flexible and shared use of them. We haven’t really considered what the complexities of doing so are, and I think this could feed nicely into some of our broader discussions about accountability and openness.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Anonymous		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/reading-simones-people-infrastructure/#comment-5</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anonymous]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 19:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=336#comment-5</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&lt;blockquote&gt;Simone&#039;s piece covers informal economies that have developed in post-apartheid, inner-city Johannesburg. He characterizes these economies as being largely supported by the provisional, collaborative practices of the city&#039;s residents. These interactions do not necessarily comply with governmental regulations, rather they are based on need and context. He claims that these conjunctions of people constitute infrastructure.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Though there is a planned nature to traditional infrastructure, it is inappropriate to apply similar predictions to the types of developments that Simone is describing. Instead, he suggests that cities are multivalent and that &quot;the critical question...raised in this ethnography of inner-city Johannesburg is how researchers, policymakers, and urban activists can practice ways of seeing and engaging urban spaces that are characterized simultaneously by regularity and provisionality.&quot; (408)&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;One of the more important aspects of the piece, for me, is the recognition that municipal and corporate entities do little to acknowledge the realities of the city and (if they do anything at all) produce interventionist programs that clash with residents&#039; ways of life. Simone notes that there is a culture that has formed here, outside of formal designations, and that the interventionist programs do not fit into or complement the way of life for these residents. He observes also that the efforts of local churches or NGOs to support a sense of &quot;community&quot; have been unsuccessful because residents see community building as a &quot;peripheral disciplinary exercise that distracts residents from developing the real skills that they need to survive.&quot; (420) Encouraging people to invest time and energy into communal development is ineffective because people need &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to be transparent to their neighbors. Their livelihood depends on different types of allegiances and responsibilities.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Simone states earlier in the reading that 90% of Johannesburg&#039;s population is made up of people who were not living there 10 years prior (411) and that many don&#039;t have the intention of staying in the city (425). They are instead there to earn a living to support their families who are likely living elsewhere. It makes sense then that residents wouldn&#039;t be interested in &quot;community building&quot; because they may not see themselves as a part of this proximate community. &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Due to the informal nature of their activities, the residents don&#039;t properly fit into the codified understanding the city. This doesn&#039;t mean that their values and concerns don&#039;t matter, but it is more likely that those interests will be left unaddressed by official bodies. In the examples above, this seems to be part of the problem. Development programs and community organization consistently misinterpret the actual needs of the residents and are rendered ineffective (by those terms). &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Codification is, of course, always value-laden and this is probably especially the case in a place with a distinct history of systemic racism. So what is considered &quot;illegitimate&quot; should viewed with a healthy dose of skepticism. That is not to say that drug dealers are doing the right thing, but perhaps it is the best option under their conditions. Simone suggests &quot;different ways of seeing&quot; among people with some power (policymakers, researchers, activists) and this seems to be a call to situate these peoples lived experiences. &lt;/blockquote&gt;]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Simone’s piece covers informal economies that have developed in post-apartheid, inner-city Johannesburg. He characterizes these economies as being largely supported by the provisional, collaborative practices of the city’s residents. These interactions do not necessarily comply with governmental regulations, rather they are based on need and context. He claims that these conjunctions of people constitute infrastructure.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Though there is a planned nature to traditional infrastructure, it is inappropriate to apply similar predictions to the types of developments that Simone is describing. Instead, he suggests that cities are multivalent and that “the critical question…raised in this ethnography of inner-city Johannesburg is how researchers, policymakers, and urban activists can practice ways of seeing and engaging urban spaces that are characterized simultaneously by regularity and provisionality.” (408)</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>One of the more important aspects of the piece, for me, is the recognition that municipal and corporate entities do little to acknowledge the realities of the city and (if they do anything at all) produce interventionist programs that clash with residents’ ways of life. Simone notes that there is a culture that has formed here, outside of formal designations, and that the interventionist programs do not fit into or complement the way of life for these residents. He observes also that the efforts of local churches or NGOs to support a sense of “community” have been unsuccessful because residents see community building as a “peripheral disciplinary exercise that distracts residents from developing the real skills that they need to survive.” (420) Encouraging people to invest time and energy into communal development is ineffective because people need <em>not</em> to be transparent to their neighbors. Their livelihood depends on different types of allegiances and responsibilities.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Simone states earlier in the reading that 90% of Johannesburg’s population is made up of people who were not living there 10 years prior (411) and that many don’t have the intention of staying in the city (425). They are instead there to earn a living to support their families who are likely living elsewhere. It makes sense then that residents wouldn’t be interested in “community building” because they may not see themselves as a part of this proximate community. </p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Due to the informal nature of their activities, the residents don’t properly fit into the codified understanding the city. This doesn’t mean that their values and concerns don’t matter, but it is more likely that those interests will be left unaddressed by official bodies. In the examples above, this seems to be part of the problem. Development programs and community organization consistently misinterpret the actual needs of the residents and are rendered ineffective (by those terms). </p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Codification is, of course, always value-laden and this is probably especially the case in a place with a distinct history of systemic racism. So what is considered “illegitimate” should viewed with a healthy dose of skepticism. That is not to say that drug dealers are doing the right thing, but perhaps it is the best option under their conditions. Simone suggests “different ways of seeing” among people with some power (policymakers, researchers, activists) and this seems to be a call to situate these peoples lived experiences. </p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
