<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Helen Verran Archives | Alex Taylor</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/tag/helen-verran/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>by Alex Taylor</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 16:15:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Reading “Counting, accounting, and accountability: Helen Verran’s relational empiricism”</title>
		<link>/counting-accounting-and-accountability/</link>
					<comments>/counting-accounting-and-accountability/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Taylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 16:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Helen Verran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[STS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Just read Martha Kenney’s “Counting, accounting, and accountability: Helen Verran’s relational empiricism”. The article is currently available through the Social Studies of Science OnlineFirst service. Intentionally or not, it sits nicely with other articles brought together to examine . Kenney, M. (2015). Counting, accounting, and accountability: Helen Verran’s relational empiricism. Social Studies of Science, 1–23. [...]</p>
<p><a class="btn btn-secondary understrap-read-more-link" href="/counting-accounting-and-accountability/">Read More...<span class="screen-reader-text"> from Reading “Counting, accounting, and accountability: Helen Verran’s relational empiricism”</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/counting-accounting-and-accountability/">Reading “Counting, accounting, and accountability: Helen Verran’s relational empiricism”</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Alex Taylor</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just read Martha Kenney’s “<a href="http://doi.org/10.1177/0306312715607413" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Counting, accounting, and accountability: Helen Verran’s relational empiricism</a>”.<br>
The article is currently available through the <a href="http://sss.sagepub.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Social Studies of Science</a> <a href="http://sss.sagepub.com/content/early/recent" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OnlineFirst</a> service. Intentionally or not, it sits nicely with other articles brought together to examine <a id="tippy_tip0_2940_anchor"></a>.</p>
<blockquote><p><a style="font-size: 145%;" href="http://doi.org/10.1177/0306312715607413" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kenney, M. (2015). Counting, accounting, and accountability: Helen Verran’s relational empiricism. Social Studies of Science, 1–23.</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Kenney’s article is very much a homage to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Helen_Verran" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Helen Verran</a> and her wonderful book <a href="http://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/S/bo3631540.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Science and an African Logic</a>. She pays special attention to Verran’s efforts at <em>decomposition</em> and frames these through a lens of accountability. Care is given by Kenny to differentiate this kind of accounting from that of “contemporary neo-liberal bureaucracies” that run the risk of strengthening “the academic culture that privileges critique and revelation over other, more subtle and creative, approaches.” <span id="more-787"></span>(p. 8)<br>
What I particularly like about Kenney’s reading of <em>Science and an African Logic</em> is the emphasis she places on Verran’s ‘generative critique’ and, in these same terms, the way we might come to understand the empirical/ethnographic account.</p>
<blockquote><p>“Verran […] helps us see ethnographic writing conventions as generative, not of true representations (tracings of real relations) but of promising fictions, echoing Strathern’s definition of ethnography as an ‘effort to create a world parallel to the perceived world’” (p. 10).</p></blockquote>
<p>For me, this is such a helpful way to think about the accounts we produce as field researchers. It gets us past questions about factual or realist representation. It reminds me of something I heard the singer PJ Harvey say on Radio 4 a while back. Talking about Harold Pinter’s poetry and ‘the poetry’ of Kubrick’s films, she evocatively describes what she sees in them:</p>
<blockquote style="font-size: 205%; font-style: italic"><a id="tippy_tip1_4670_anchor"></a></blockquote>
<p>As with Pinter and Kubrick, then, I appreciate Kenney reminding us that ethnographic accounts such as Verran’s must be written/read as “an alternative way of figuring and paying attention to differences that may enable different forms of response and participation.” (p. 11)</p>
<div class="tippy" data-title="<em>care</em>" data-showheader="false" data-anchor="#tippy_tip0_2940_anchor">See, for example, Martin, A., Myers, N., &amp; Viseu, A. (2015). <a href="http://doi.org/10.1177/0306312715602073" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The politics of care in technoscience</a>. Social Studies of Science, 1–17.</div>
<div class="tippy" data-title="'There is so much space where the truth can enter.'" data-showheader="false" data-anchor="#tippy_tip1_4670_anchor">I dashed to make a written note of this, but have since found the interview online, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QsJ4X3TlTsM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> — time = 9:21.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/counting-accounting-and-accountability/">Reading “Counting, accounting, and accountability: Helen Verran’s relational empiricism”</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Alex Taylor</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/counting-accounting-and-accountability/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
