<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Back to interaction (a reply to Barry)	</title>
	<atom:link href="http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/</link>
	<description>by Alex Taylor</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 12:55:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: David Martin		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-31</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Martin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 12:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=755#comment-31</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I want to come back to ‘interaction’ in the original article: I agree wholeheartedly with the point of the article but I don’t think the more radical take on agency is required to get there (maybe it is just your particular route). It is absolutely clear that a narrow focus on interaction at an interface is an incredibly simplified way of considering things. It has led to people extending the ‘interface’ beyond a screen and input device (as you note) to something that relates to wider socio-material assemblies, societal functioning, whatever. It can also be hard to locate just where an interface might be. Think about high frequency algorithmic trading –algorithms competing with other algorithms that forms the majority of trades in markets. Can we understand it by looking at a terminal screen? Nope. What can we understand about it by understanding traders interactions with technologies for showing something of its operation? I don’t have an answer to that but it’s an interesting question. What do the designers of the algorithms understand about their operation and potential impact? Another good question. There is another interesting thing that comes out of this though – the failure or success of technically instantiated and driven markets that work in this way has real impacts on peoples’ lives such that their agency (freedom of choice) may be curbed, as they suffer wage pressure, etc. These are sort of reverberating impacts rather than proximal or direct ones.
This happens in a far more mundane and direct way, when call centre worker interaction with customers is constrained by scripts embedded on technology. This is motivated ideologically – the idea is that there is a problem if agents are given too much autonomy. Too much autonomy means they are not under control. This is often positioned like it is just about ensuring standardisation, ensuring uniform customer service, protecting against agents going off-script and misrepresenting the company or giving bad advice. However, while there is some truth in this it is also about de-skilling – experienced and knowledgeable agents are expensive. Through scripts and standardisation you sell the dream that the script takes care of the work so the agent does not need to think for themselves. This reduces you labour costs, but in my experience (and I have quite a lot of it in this domain) it generally lowers the quality of service, particularly for complex and idiosyncratic inquiries. It makes call centre work low paid, high surveillance and controlled work, and so in this way technology is rather directly employed to take workers’ agency away (and their sense of self-worth etc.). But people are behind it too. And by the way it is precisely these types of move that gut and shape a service to such an extent – i.e. render it robotic and of poor quality - that the challenge for automation becomes a lot more simple, i.e. outperforming a crap service with a disengaged workforce is a lesser challenge for an automated agent. So while I don’t think technology has agency, it certainly has the potential and the actuality to provide or take away human agency. And I do strongly agree that a narrow focus on interaction prevents people from seeing things of wider importance in terms of impact, and I would even go as for to say that some of this way of thinking is designed precisely as a set of blinkers to stop people thinking about the wider (political) import of what they are doing.
On the subject of ontology – I kind of agree with both Alex and Alison in a general sense – but I think that in making this move there is a danger that you represent a Western view as monolithic when it is very far from this. If we consider religion, faith and spirituality in the broadest and most diverse sense you will see that human/material object dichotomies suddenly break and become a lot more complex, which is one of the very clear points that Winch made in (his sarcastically titled) ‘Understanding A Primitive Society’. And similarly when I read things like Eduardo Viveiros de Castro I think there may be an over-emphasis and magnification aimed at making the strange, stranger and in a way that is too neat. Back to Winch – a key point of his was of Western anthropology doing two things simultaneously – simplifying and exaggerating Western scientific rationality like it was universal in Western life while at the same time painting the tribal culture as exotic, irrational and bizarre, when it was actually pretty understandable and had its own rationality.
Therefore in my book there isn’t a satisfactory ‘ontological’ answer to these types of questions – they need careful working out in relation to particular instances. In many cases, it may well be doing a disservice to raise these endogenous definitions within everyday settings of the conceptions of differences and relations between people and things and their attributes to an ontological level. Can these really be seen as ontological questions for those involved? What would indicate that a question was ontological rather than purely practical (or maybe political)?]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I want to come back to ‘interaction’ in the original article: I agree wholeheartedly with the point of the article but I don’t think the more radical take on agency is required to get there (maybe it is just your particular route). It is absolutely clear that a narrow focus on interaction at an interface is an incredibly simplified way of considering things. It has led to people extending the ‘interface’ beyond a screen and input device (as you note) to something that relates to wider socio-material assemblies, societal functioning, whatever. It can also be hard to locate just where an interface might be. Think about high frequency algorithmic trading –algorithms competing with other algorithms that forms the majority of trades in markets. Can we understand it by looking at a terminal screen? Nope. What can we understand about it by understanding traders interactions with technologies for showing something of its operation? I don’t have an answer to that but it’s an interesting question. What do the designers of the algorithms understand about their operation and potential impact? Another good question. There is another interesting thing that comes out of this though – the failure or success of technically instantiated and driven markets that work in this way has real impacts on peoples’ lives such that their agency (freedom of choice) may be curbed, as they suffer wage pressure, etc. These are sort of reverberating impacts rather than proximal or direct ones.<br>
This happens in a far more mundane and direct way, when call centre worker interaction with customers is constrained by scripts embedded on technology. This is motivated ideologically – the idea is that there is a problem if agents are given too much autonomy. Too much autonomy means they are not under control. This is often positioned like it is just about ensuring standardisation, ensuring uniform customer service, protecting against agents going off-script and misrepresenting the company or giving bad advice. However, while there is some truth in this it is also about de-skilling – experienced and knowledgeable agents are expensive. Through scripts and standardisation you sell the dream that the script takes care of the work so the agent does not need to think for themselves. This reduces you labour costs, but in my experience (and I have quite a lot of it in this domain) it generally lowers the quality of service, particularly for complex and idiosyncratic inquiries. It makes call centre work low paid, high surveillance and controlled work, and so in this way technology is rather directly employed to take workers’ agency away (and their sense of self-worth etc.). But people are behind it too. And by the way it is precisely these types of move that gut and shape a service to such an extent – i.e. render it robotic and of poor quality — that the challenge for automation becomes a lot more simple, i.e. outperforming a crap service with a disengaged workforce is a lesser challenge for an automated agent. So while I don’t think technology has agency, it certainly has the potential and the actuality to provide or take away human agency. And I do strongly agree that a narrow focus on interaction prevents people from seeing things of wider importance in terms of impact, and I would even go as for to say that some of this way of thinking is designed precisely as a set of blinkers to stop people thinking about the wider (political) import of what they are doing.<br>
On the subject of ontology – I kind of agree with both Alex and Alison in a general sense – but I think that in making this move there is a danger that you represent a Western view as monolithic when it is very far from this. If we consider religion, faith and spirituality in the broadest and most diverse sense you will see that human/material object dichotomies suddenly break and become a lot more complex, which is one of the very clear points that Winch made in (his sarcastically titled) ‘Understanding A Primitive Society’. And similarly when I read things like Eduardo Viveiros de Castro I think there may be an over-emphasis and magnification aimed at making the strange, stranger and in a way that is too neat. Back to Winch – a key point of his was of Western anthropology doing two things simultaneously – simplifying and exaggerating Western scientific rationality like it was universal in Western life while at the same time painting the tribal culture as exotic, irrational and bizarre, when it was actually pretty understandable and had its own rationality.<br>
Therefore in my book there isn’t a satisfactory ‘ontological’ answer to these types of questions – they need careful working out in relation to particular instances. In many cases, it may well be doing a disservice to raise these endogenous definitions within everyday settings of the conceptions of differences and relations between people and things and their attributes to an ontological level. Can these really be seen as ontological questions for those involved? What would indicate that a question was ontological rather than purely practical (or maybe political)?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Barry Brown		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-30</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Barry Brown]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 09:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=755#comment-30</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-29&quot;&gt;Alison Marlin&lt;/a&gt;.

This led to a nice offline conv with Stuart reeves who was visiting us last week - he mentioned that  bob and Wes have a nice unpublished piece which touches on many of the points here.
http://www.sharrockandanderson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Ethical-Algorithms.pdf
One little last thing is to mention latour&#039;s use of humor. From a continental perspective latour is trying to keep in play a skepticism towardst claims.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-29">Alison Marlin</a>.</p>
<p>This led to a nice offline conv with Stuart reeves who was visiting us last week — he mentioned that  bob and Wes have a nice unpublished piece which touches on many of the points here.<br>
<a href="http://www.sharrockandanderson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Ethical-Algorithms.pdf" rel="nofollow ugc">http://www.sharrockandanderson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Ethical-Algorithms.pdf</a><br>
One little last thing is to mention latour’s use of humor. From a continental perspective latour is trying to keep in play a skepticism towardst claims.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Alison Marlin		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-29</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alison Marlin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 14:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=755#comment-29</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What an incredibly thoughtful and engaged set of comments to a blog post - this flies in the face of all received wisdom about online commenting!  Many thanks to all of you for trying to work through some of these complicated issues in a public forum where we may all benefit from it, and especially to Alex, for your original piece in Interactions which sparked it all.
This debate for and against what we might call &#039;relational&#039; or &#039;material semiotic&#039; approaches sprouts periodically in different places, but I found this iteration interesting and helpful for thinking about a couple of the key points of the debate.  I should note that I am closer to Alex in thinking than to Barry or David.
The first difference that always arises is over the nature of reality - whether, as Barry argues, people and things, bodies and minds, are really different and it is a dangerous categorical mistake to behave otherwise.  This one seems to be an intractable problem, never successfully resolved.  To me, Science Studies has shown repeatedly that there are many ways of doing the world, of which the modern Euro-American version of matter set in time and space and a duality of mind and body, is only one, and not necessarily the most successful.  Questions of truth and reality are important within this Euro-American frame, but not within many of the others, including the ones mobilised by some of the theorists Alex has been referencing.  It is hard to resolve an issue (the nature of a stable reality) which for one side is crucial, and for the other is somewhat irrelevant.
Another problem seems to revolve around agency, and the patent absurdity of assigning human-like agency to objects.  I agree with Barry that this has a certain shock value which can be useful in limited cases, but that otherwise if we take things as behaving in human-like ways we will mostly be lead into difficulties.  It seems to me that a re-doing of the human/non-human binary requires a simultaneous re-doing of the closely related object/subject binary, and of what it is to act.  The sorts of agency that we attribute to humans in a modern Euro-American frame, with their underlying implications of freedom and choice, are clearly not appropriate when the discrete human subject is abandoned as the source of action.  (Abrahamsson et al&#039;s recent piece in Environment and Planning D: Society and Space, &#039;Living with omega-3: New materialism and enduring concerns, talks about this.)   A different frame needs to mobilise different concepts of how acts happen, and how such acts are distributed among entities.
I would tend to agree with Alex that the term &#039;interaction&#039; is problematic, embedding as it does implications of two separate and prior entities (people and things) which then interact.  But then language always embeds within it a set of metaphysical assumptions, in some cases ones we wish to embrace, and in other cases ones that we find problematic.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What an incredibly thoughtful and engaged set of comments to a blog post — this flies in the face of all received wisdom about online commenting!  Many thanks to all of you for trying to work through some of these complicated issues in a public forum where we may all benefit from it, and especially to Alex, for your original piece in Interactions which sparked it all.<br>
This debate for and against what we might call ‘relational’ or ‘material semiotic’ approaches sprouts periodically in different places, but I found this iteration interesting and helpful for thinking about a couple of the key points of the debate.  I should note that I am closer to Alex in thinking than to Barry or David.<br>
The first difference that always arises is over the nature of reality — whether, as Barry argues, people and things, bodies and minds, are really different and it is a dangerous categorical mistake to behave otherwise.  This one seems to be an intractable problem, never successfully resolved.  To me, Science Studies has shown repeatedly that there are many ways of doing the world, of which the modern Euro-American version of matter set in time and space and a duality of mind and body, is only one, and not necessarily the most successful.  Questions of truth and reality are important within this Euro-American frame, but not within many of the others, including the ones mobilised by some of the theorists Alex has been referencing.  It is hard to resolve an issue (the nature of a stable reality) which for one side is crucial, and for the other is somewhat irrelevant.<br>
Another problem seems to revolve around agency, and the patent absurdity of assigning human-like agency to objects.  I agree with Barry that this has a certain shock value which can be useful in limited cases, but that otherwise if we take things as behaving in human-like ways we will mostly be lead into difficulties.  It seems to me that a re-doing of the human/non-human binary requires a simultaneous re-doing of the closely related object/subject binary, and of what it is to act.  The sorts of agency that we attribute to humans in a modern Euro-American frame, with their underlying implications of freedom and choice, are clearly not appropriate when the discrete human subject is abandoned as the source of action.  (Abrahamsson et al’s recent piece in Environment and Planning D: Society and Space, ‘Living with omega‑3: New materialism and enduring concerns, talks about this.)   A different frame needs to mobilise different concepts of how acts happen, and how such acts are distributed among entities.<br>
I would tend to agree with Alex that the term ‘interaction’ is problematic, embedding as it does implications of two separate and prior entities (people and things) which then interact.  But then language always embeds within it a set of metaphysical assumptions, in some cases ones we wish to embrace, and in other cases ones that we find problematic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: David Martin		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-28</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Martin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 10:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=755#comment-28</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Alex - judging by your last post we are closer on these matter, most I agree with but I think you are hard on Mike mainly because he is a proponent of not letting your political affiliations produce an analysis that misrepresents the situation for your own purposes. This can lead you into the opposite problem of ironicizing without making a position clear. Mary Midgley talks about how a similar problem occurred when analytic philosophers approached moral philosophy - good on describing the landscape but disingenious in counting themselves out from having anything productive to say. Can you really not take sides in a discussion of morals, the nature of the topic kind of demands it? And thank you for contributing too Barry. Now I need to have a think about this as well, go and read some of the references, and since it&#039;s Saturday I wish you both a good weekend!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alex — judging by your last post we are closer on these matter, most I agree with but I think you are hard on Mike mainly because he is a proponent of not letting your political affiliations produce an analysis that misrepresents the situation for your own purposes. This can lead you into the opposite problem of ironicizing without making a position clear. Mary Midgley talks about how a similar problem occurred when analytic philosophers approached moral philosophy — good on describing the landscape but disingenious in counting themselves out from having anything productive to say. Can you really not take sides in a discussion of morals, the nature of the topic kind of demands it? And thank you for contributing too Barry. Now I need to have a think about this as well, go and read some of the references, and since it’s Saturday I wish you both a good weekend!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Barry Brown		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-27</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Barry Brown]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 13:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=755#comment-27</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thanks Alex and Dave for this discussion — I hadn’t quite expected all his from a Friday afternoon email!
Agreed that categorization is a valuable and perennial concern,  I worry though  whether it can really be sensibly treated as a singular thing — like representation, its diversity might be too much.  Categorizing fish I suspect is quite different from the final prices of the Paris Bourse.
As for the agency discussion —like Dave I was mainly concerned with the different attributes and actions that go alongside those categories. And at times poetic license may lead us to a muddle.  Morgan Ames very nice paper on charismatic technology at the århus conference, was the case I was thinking of.  I wasn’t convinced that attributing charisma to OLPC helps our understanding (which I thought was a straightforward category mistake), unlike Morgan’s fieldwork which surely does.
To be honest though what I found most interesting in Alex’s original article was the potential to reflecting again upon interaction as a concept. And the potential that such a thing might have for transfusing a little from STS without killing HCI.  The conversation analysts have this thing where they emphasize the primacy of *the next turn* in talk for building and understanding of interaction, and I wondered if HCI’s focus on interaction had sort of had a similar affect.  It limits the ability to attribute and expand discussion without limit.  As famously in three mile island, the interface of the nuclear power station matters. Yet in turn as Alex points out, the interaction is part of all these different things going on around (say) the deployment of city bikes. So I wondered if the term might be a good place to work out some of our confusions.
But thanks again!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks Alex and Dave for this discussion — I hadn’t quite expected all his from a Friday afternoon email!<br>
Agreed that categorization is a valuable and perennial concern,  I worry though  whether it can really be sensibly treated as a singular thing — like representation, its diversity might be too much.  Categorizing fish I suspect is quite different from the final prices of the Paris Bourse.<br>
As for the agency discussion —like Dave I was mainly concerned with the different attributes and actions that go alongside those categories. And at times poetic license may lead us to a muddle.  Morgan Ames very nice paper on charismatic technology at the århus conference, was the case I was thinking of.  I wasn’t convinced that attributing charisma to OLPC helps our understanding (which I thought was a straightforward category mistake), unlike Morgan’s fieldwork which surely does.<br>
To be honest though what I found most interesting in Alex’s original article was the potential to reflecting again upon interaction as a concept. And the potential that such a thing might have for transfusing a little from STS without killing HCI.  The conversation analysts have this thing where they emphasize the primacy of *the next turn* in talk for building and understanding of interaction, and I wondered if HCI’s focus on interaction had sort of had a similar affect.  It limits the ability to attribute and expand discussion without limit.  As famously in three mile island, the interface of the nuclear power station matters. Yet in turn as Alex points out, the interaction is part of all these different things going on around (say) the deployment of city bikes. So I wondered if the term might be a good place to work out some of our confusions.<br>
But thanks again!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Alex		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-26</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 13:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=755#comment-26</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-23&quot;&gt;David Martin&lt;/a&gt;.

Ah, well this makes me think we are still in the same ball park. Your &#039;only problem&#039; with Lynch is mine as well, though for me it is not a whimsical oversight on his part, but a very big and important one. It demonstrates a refusal to recognise he is in some way inside all this mess, and very much a part of the sorting and organising of things/people that he would claim to be studying - from &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; I do not know. Moreover, and relatedly, it shows he fails to recognise that he himself operates in and sustains what Goodwin calls a &#039;lifeworld&#039;. He enacts, along with an assortment of tools and procedures, a certain kind of world with its epistemes and ontics, and the normativities that travel with them. It is peculiar to write this out of his otherwise deeply insightful accounts of science and ordinary life. And, I agree too, this is where feminist readings would offer a productive counterpoint. So, perhaps we have some common ground here?
I do find Barad dense in her writing (possibly overly so), but I admit to subscribing to her kind of (agential) realism and her insistence on the possibility of &#039;better worlds&#039;. It is worth reading Pinch&#039;s review, if you haven&#039;t, and Barad&#039;s retort. If anything it shows some of the differences between their two sides, and how they choose to engage with the &#039;troubles&#039;. I would be very interested to hear your thoughts on Haraway&#039;s 1988 piece as it is in line with your problem with Lynch.
And, I would agree with you about the many settings in which people comfortably reference subject-object positions (for lack of a better phrase) and human-thing binaries. There are certainly no shortage of places, activities, events, etc. in which that idea of being in the world is present. I have two brief things to say about that. One, if we were the kind of anthropologists who spent their time in far flung places, not like ours, would we accept after long enough that their &#039;voodoo&#039; had some truth in it? Perhaps we might, but the point here is that we might be just as interested in how their truth claims (alongside and interleaved with ours) come into being - not whether they would be actually true or not, but how they constitute a kind of life (I like Helen Verran&#039;s work in this realm). Two, what I find in my own empirical work is that people seem to work with multiple registers, for instance, talking about subject-object positions and in the same breath do something that startlingly unravels any stark distinction between the binaries. I&#039;m not inclined to privilege either of these, but instead to wonder how we work with multiplicity and the ways this opens us up to other ways of being.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-23">David Martin</a>.</p>
<p>Ah, well this makes me think we are still in the same ball park. Your ‘only problem’ with Lynch is mine as well, though for me it is not a whimsical oversight on his part, but a very big and important one. It demonstrates a refusal to recognise he is in some way inside all this mess, and very much a part of the sorting and organising of things/people that he would claim to be studying — from <em>where</em> I do not know. Moreover, and relatedly, it shows he fails to recognise that he himself operates in and sustains what Goodwin calls a ‘lifeworld’. He enacts, along with an assortment of tools and procedures, a certain kind of world with its epistemes and ontics, and the normativities that travel with them. It is peculiar to write this out of his otherwise deeply insightful accounts of science and ordinary life. And, I agree too, this is where feminist readings would offer a productive counterpoint. So, perhaps we have some common ground here?<br>
I do find Barad dense in her writing (possibly overly so), but I admit to subscribing to her kind of (agential) realism and her insistence on the possibility of ‘better worlds’. It is worth reading Pinch’s review, if you haven’t, and Barad’s retort. If anything it shows some of the differences between their two sides, and how they choose to engage with the ‘troubles’. I would be very interested to hear your thoughts on Haraway’s 1988 piece as it is in line with your problem with Lynch.<br>
And, I would agree with you about the many settings in which people comfortably reference subject-object positions (for lack of a better phrase) and human-thing binaries. There are certainly no shortage of places, activities, events, etc. in which that idea of being in the world is present. I have two brief things to say about that. One, if we were the kind of anthropologists who spent their time in far flung places, not like ours, would we accept after long enough that their ‘voodoo’ had some truth in it? Perhaps we might, but the point here is that we might be just as interested in how their truth claims (alongside and interleaved with ours) come into being — not whether they would be actually true or not, but how they constitute a kind of life (I like Helen Verran’s work in this realm). Two, what I find in my own empirical work is that people seem to work with multiple registers, for instance, talking about subject-object positions and in the same breath do something that startlingly unravels any stark distinction between the binaries. I’m not inclined to privilege either of these, but instead to wonder how we work with multiplicity and the ways this opens us up to other ways of being.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Alex		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-25</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 12:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=755#comment-25</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-24&quot;&gt;David Martin&lt;/a&gt;.

:-)]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-24">David Martin</a>.</p>
<p>🙂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: David Martin		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-24</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Martin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 12:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=755#comment-24</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[vodoo - it&#039;s a special form of voodoo ;-)]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>vodoo — it’s a special form of voodoo 😉</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: David Martin		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-23</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Martin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 12:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=755#comment-23</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-22&quot;&gt;Alex&lt;/a&gt;.

Hi Alex, just as I think we approach maybe we drift further apart. I must admit I find Lynch on ontography the most convincing and the only problem I have with him is that he doesn&#039;t want to make his moral/political position clear, and instead he poses a few questions and makes a few points that indicate his stance without pushing through a moral critique of definitions of natural, GM modified, labelling etc. as allowed by current US law. So here is a point where a feminist reading also has it&#039;s foothold, the critique of certain ontological arrangements that e.g. favour men in some way, as being &#039;natural&#039;.
It&#039;s weird, I know she has many fans, but I haven&#039;t been able to see what&#039;s so impressive about Barad - I see some interesting things but I don&#039;t think she is correct in her position, ontologically. I need to read Haraway (and some of the others) and get back to you.
Final point, on your third way proposal: I&#039;m totally fine about the idea that we shouldn&#039;t presume an a priori human/material object separation when doing our studies but I do want to point out that overwhelmingly the people we study draw various clear separations - and one of the clearest is around sentience, thinking, morality, emotion, reasoning, agency and so forth. There are borderline cases, and there are special cases when elements of these things, in limited, different capacities are found in objects (a vodoo doll for example), but that does not mean there is no difference in between people and vodoo dolls to those involved in those activities. And these are not the most common cases. In most cases there are some very clear separations.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-22">Alex</a>.</p>
<p>Hi Alex, just as I think we approach maybe we drift further apart. I must admit I find Lynch on ontography the most convincing and the only problem I have with him is that he doesn’t want to make his moral/political position clear, and instead he poses a few questions and makes a few points that indicate his stance without pushing through a moral critique of definitions of natural, GM modified, labelling etc. as allowed by current US law. So here is a point where a feminist reading also has it’s foothold, the critique of certain ontological arrangements that e.g. favour men in some way, as being ‘natural’.<br>
It’s weird, I know she has many fans, but I haven’t been able to see what’s so impressive about Barad — I see some interesting things but I don’t think she is correct in her position, ontologically. I need to read Haraway (and some of the others) and get back to you.<br>
Final point, on your third way proposal: I’m totally fine about the idea that we shouldn’t presume an a priori human/material object separation when doing our studies but I do want to point out that overwhelmingly the people we study draw various clear separations — and one of the clearest is around sentience, thinking, morality, emotion, reasoning, agency and so forth. There are borderline cases, and there are special cases when elements of these things, in limited, different capacities are found in objects (a vodoo doll for example), but that does not mean there is no difference in between people and vodoo dolls to those involved in those activities. And these are not the most common cases. In most cases there are some very clear separations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Alex		</title>
		<link>http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-22</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 10:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ast.io/?p=755#comment-22</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-21&quot;&gt;David Martin&lt;/a&gt;.

Ah, constructivism! That is a thorny but important issue to bring up here. I should say straight out that I am not a proponent of social constructivism, in any of its flavours. Inspired by the likes of Haraway and Barad, to my mind constructivisim had its value, but ultimately, it is just the other side of the determinist/reductionist standpoint - it served as a counter balance to old school materialism, but in the end it simply restates the clumsy social-material, subject-object divisions we are dealing with here. Haraway deals with this so neatly in her piece from way back in &#039;88, which still seems so full of truths.  Bellacasa (2011) and Barad (2011) give us some slightly more contemporary points of reference.
So, as for death, my interest is in precisely how we can come to be confident about death, and what it is. I would not dispute that death has some biological/organic basis; this is, indeed, a matter of fact. However, can&#039;t we - shouldn&#039;t we - ask ourselves how we are able to determine, use and talk about these kinds of facts? Surely, it has been a progression of instruments, organisational alignments, expertise, etc. that has given rise to the fact that death is just this sort of thing? The question is not whether these facts are true or not, but how they have come to be true - and in being true what other worlds are being subordinated, overshadowed, cast aside, etc., and what other worlds might we come to, or want to, live in?
I suppose I see these metaphysical meanderings being about getting us back to the phenomena. Yes (Lynch&#039;s shortsightedness aside*), let us get back to how these things are done on the ground, how worlds are made, always already made. What (and who&#039;s) purpose does it serve to keep finding ways to separate things and people? It does exactly as you say and imposes a view from outside (or as Haraway would call it &#039;nowhere&#039;). In this light, can I offer a 3rd proposition to the two you state? What if we didn&#039;t worry about the differences between humans and objects at all, and as you say concentrate on the phenomena? It&#039;s not, i., that we should come with some preformed ideas of both, or, ii., that we should see degrees of different sorts agencies, but that in the end we might still imagine some line of separation. Rather, it&#039;s an openness to seeing how worlds are made and recognising it is always the bricolage of actors (of all kinds) that brings them into being. The question is always how, and we must ask that of ourselves too, along with the question how &quot;it could be otherwise&quot; (Woolgar and Lezaun 2013).
* I feel remiss in not taking this on, but it is a big fish/salmon to fry, so I will leave it to others far better qualified to do so. No doubt you have seen articles in the same &lt;a 0=&quot;href=&#034;http://sss.sagepub.com/content/43/3.toc&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;special issue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and it is also worth tracing the follow up discussion &lt;a href=&quot;http://sss.sagepub.com/content/45/3.toc&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
Barad, K. M. (2011). Erasers and erasures: Pinch&#039;s unfortunate ‘uncertainty principle’. &lt;em&gt;Social Studies of Science&lt;/em&gt;, 41(3), 443–454.
Bellacasa, de la, M. P. (2011). Matters of care in technoscience: Assembling neglected things. &lt;em&gt;Social Studies of Science&lt;/em&gt;, 41(1), 85–106.
Haraway, D. (1988). Situated Knowledges: The Science Question in Feminism and the Privilege of Partial Perspective. &lt;em&gt;Feminist Studies&lt;/em&gt;, 14(3), 575–599.
Lynch, M. (2013). Ontography: Investigating the production of things, deflating ontology. &lt;em&gt;Social Studies of Science&lt;/em&gt;, 43(3), 444–462.
Woolgar, S., &amp; Lezaun, J. (2013). The wrong bin bag: A turn to ontology in science and technology studies? &lt;em&gt;Social Studies of Science&lt;/em&gt;, 43(3), 321–340.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://ast.io/back-to-interaction/#comment-21">David Martin</a>.</p>
<p>Ah, constructivism! That is a thorny but important issue to bring up here. I should say straight out that I am not a proponent of social constructivism, in any of its flavours. Inspired by the likes of Haraway and Barad, to my mind constructivisim had its value, but ultimately, it is just the other side of the determinist/reductionist standpoint — it served as a counter balance to old school materialism, but in the end it simply restates the clumsy social-material, subject-object divisions we are dealing with here. Haraway deals with this so neatly in her piece from way back in ’88, which still seems so full of truths.  Bellacasa (2011) and Barad (2011) give us some slightly more contemporary points of reference.<br>
So, as for death, my interest is in precisely how we can come to be confident about death, and what it is. I would not dispute that death has some biological/organic basis; this is, indeed, a matter of fact. However, can’t we — shouldn’t we — ask ourselves how we are able to determine, use and talk about these kinds of facts? Surely, it has been a progression of instruments, organisational alignments, expertise, etc. that has given rise to the fact that death is just this sort of thing? The question is not whether these facts are true or not, but how they have come to be true — and in being true what other worlds are being subordinated, overshadowed, cast aside, etc., and what other worlds might we come to, or want to, live in?<br>
I suppose I see these metaphysical meanderings being about getting us back to the phenomena. Yes (Lynch’s shortsightedness aside*), let us get back to how these things are done on the ground, how worlds are made, always already made. What (and who’s) purpose does it serve to keep finding ways to separate things and people? It does exactly as you say and imposes a view from outside (or as Haraway would call it ‘nowhere’). In this light, can I offer a 3rd proposition to the two you state? What if we didn’t worry about the differences between humans and objects at all, and as you say concentrate on the phenomena? It’s not, i., that we should come with some preformed ideas of both, or, ii., that we should see degrees of different sorts agencies, but that in the end we might still imagine some line of separation. Rather, it’s an openness to seeing how worlds are made and recognising it is always the bricolage of actors (of all kinds) that brings them into being. The question is always how, and we must ask that of ourselves too, along with the question how “it could be otherwise” (Woolgar and Lezaun 2013).<br>
* I feel remiss in not taking this on, but it is a big fish/salmon to fry, so I will leave it to others far better qualified to do so. No doubt you have seen articles in the same <a rel="nofollow"><em>special issue</em></a> and it is also worth tracing the follow up discussion <a href="http://sss.sagepub.com/content/45/3.toc" rel="nofollow"><em>here</em></a>.<br>
Barad, K. M. (2011). Erasers and erasures: Pinch’s unfortunate ‘uncertainty principle’. <em>Social Studies of Science</em>, 41(3), 443–454.<br>
Bellacasa, de la, M. P. (2011). Matters of care in technoscience: Assembling neglected things. <em>Social Studies of Science</em>, 41(1), 85–106.<br>
Haraway, D. (1988). Situated Knowledges: The Science Question in Feminism and the Privilege of Partial Perspective. <em>Feminist Studies</em>, 14(3), 575–599.<br>
Lynch, M. (2013). Ontography: Investigating the production of things, deflating ontology. <em>Social Studies of Science</em>, 43(3), 444–462.<br>
Woolgar, S., &amp; Lezaun, J. (2013). The wrong bin bag: A turn to ontology in science and technology studies? <em>Social Studies of Science</em>, 43(3), 321–340.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
