<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: “The promiscuity of interaction”	</title>
	<atom:link href="/promiscuity-of-interaction/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/promiscuity-of-interaction/</link>
	<description>by Alex Taylor</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 12:10:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Stuart Reeves		</title>
		<link>/promiscuity-of-interaction/#comment-40</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stuart Reeves]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 12:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1042#comment-40</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A very nice summary indeed.
I end up thinking back again and again to two questions for us: &quot;what&#039;s at play&quot; and finding &quot;where it&#039;s at play&quot;. I think the frustration you speak of might arise from the new challenges that face us in HCI in dealing more seriously with the worlds technology is implicated in. (Which seems to be ever more things.)
I like Star&#039;s observations too; they are interesting, insightful and so on, but in the end they are deeply unlikely to be at play interactionally in how many people actually materially use a laptop. So it&#039;s not necessarily a deficiency of a (say) interaction analysis of laptop use. But rather it&#039;s a deficiency in our own abilities to find places where such matters are surfaced and brought into play.
So if we are interested in looking at the entanglements we may need to look somewhere else: e.g., the factory or the clean room. And that&#039;s hard (but worthwhile).
The confusion (as I&#039;d argue) over &#039;agency&#039; is another one of these problems. The answer is not necessarily, I think, to start trying to locate agency in things but rather to work out where it&#039;s at play, where it is relevant. Again, this is a hard problem because it probably means we need to start going places that we haven&#039;t before.
In short I think we need to find different sites, places, etc.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A very nice summary indeed.<br>
I end up thinking back again and again to two questions for us: “what’s at play” and finding “where it’s at play”. I think the frustration you speak of might arise from the new challenges that face us in HCI in dealing more seriously with the worlds technology is implicated in. (Which seems to be ever more things.)<br>
I like Star’s observations too; they are interesting, insightful and so on, but in the end they are deeply unlikely to be at play interactionally in how many people actually materially use a laptop. So it’s not necessarily a deficiency of a (say) interaction analysis of laptop use. But rather it’s a deficiency in our own abilities to find places where such matters are surfaced and brought into play.<br>
So if we are interested in looking at the entanglements we may need to look somewhere else: e.g., the factory or the clean room. And that’s hard (but worthwhile).<br>
The confusion (as I’d argue) over ‘agency’ is another one of these problems. The answer is not necessarily, I think, to start trying to locate agency in things but rather to work out where it’s at play, where it is relevant. Again, this is a hard problem because it probably means we need to start going places that we haven’t before.<br>
In short I think we need to find different sites, places, etc.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Barry Brown		</title>
		<link>/promiscuity-of-interaction/#comment-39</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Barry Brown]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 01:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1042#comment-39</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[THANKS alex, a thoughtful and engaging summary of the day!  This all comes to life to me if I think of something like Uber, where just thinking about the &#039;interaction&#039; rather misses &#039;where the action is&#039;. I&#039;m going to ask the old question again - whats your ideas for how we can move from being descriptive and responsive to creative and disruptive?]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>THANKS alex, a thoughtful and engaging summary of the day!  This all comes to life to me if I think of something like Uber, where just thinking about the ‘interaction’ rather misses ‘where the action is’. I’m going to ask the old question again — whats your ideas for how we can move from being descriptive and responsive to creative and disruptive?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: drannalcox		</title>
		<link>/promiscuity-of-interaction/#comment-38</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[drannalcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 17:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1042#comment-38</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you&#039;re keen to discuss the concept of interactivity further then there&#039;s another opportunity at the Third International Conference on Interactivity, Language and Cognition http://www.issilc.org/conferences which is being held at Kingston University, London. The conference will host a workshop on Thursday 30th of June, 9.00-11.00am entitled: “From computers to cultures: A cross-disciplinary study of the concept of interactivity - The study of interactivity spreads over many disciplines and topics, from human-computer interactions, interactive learning, interactive communication, cross-cultural interaction, interaction management, interactive marketing or interactive decision-making and problem solving, to name a few. Yet, it remains an elusive concept which may be used to describe processes taking place in different systems (cultures, organisations, groups, dyads, human artefact systems) with different social, cognitive and behavioural outcomes. This workshop will bring together scholars from different disciplines with the objective to share and discuss different approaches to study interactivity and its impact on cognition and behaviour.&quot;  Speakers: Jennifer Misyak (Cultural interactions), Anna Cox (Human-Computer Interaction), Chris Howes (Interactive communication), Rob Thurner (Interactive marketing), Gaelle Vallee-Tourangeau (Interactivity in distributed cognition), &#038; Laure Cabantous (actor-network theory).]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you’re keen to discuss the concept of interactivity further then there’s another opportunity at the Third International Conference on Interactivity, Language and Cognition <a href="http://www.issilc.org/conferences" rel="nofollow ugc">http://www.issilc.org/conferences</a> which is being held at Kingston University, London. The conference will host a workshop on Thursday 30th of June, 9.00–11.00am entitled: “From computers to cultures: A cross-disciplinary study of the concept of interactivity — The study of interactivity spreads over many disciplines and topics, from human-computer interactions, interactive learning, interactive communication, cross-cultural interaction, interaction management, interactive marketing or interactive decision-making and problem solving, to name a few. Yet, it remains an elusive concept which may be used to describe processes taking place in different systems (cultures, organisations, groups, dyads, human artefact systems) with different social, cognitive and behavioural outcomes. This workshop will bring together scholars from different disciplines with the objective to share and discuss different approaches to study interactivity and its impact on cognition and behaviour.”  Speakers: Jennifer Misyak (Cultural interactions), Anna Cox (Human-Computer Interaction), Chris Howes (Interactive communication), Rob Thurner (Interactive marketing), Gaelle Vallee-Tourangeau (Interactivity in distributed cognition), &amp; Laure Cabantous (actor-network theory).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
